<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex Sonneveld</title>
    <description>A personal blog and writings of an individual by the name of Alex Sonneveld, sometimes known as Sonna throughout the interwebs, a Ruby/Web developer and Video Games enthusiast.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 18:48:29 +1100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 18:48:29 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sample Page</title>
        <description>&lt;div id=&quot;toc&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;toctitle&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;sectlevel1&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-example&quot;&gt;code example&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;preamble&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a sample page composed in AsciiDoc.
Jekyll converts it to HTML using &lt;a href=&quot;http://asciidoctor.org&quot;&gt;Asciidoctor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;code-example&quot;&gt;code example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;app.rb&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;L1&quot; class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;sinatra&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;L2&quot; class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;L3&quot; class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;/hi&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;L4&quot; class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello World!&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;L5&quot; class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 16:48:58 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/sample/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/sample/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to my website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So … this has been long time coming. It has been something I have been meaning
to do for a while now, however never had the either the motivation or the time
to commit to just writing, let alone building a website (despite spinning up a
static website generator here and there).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never really wanted something that be considered bloated or overkill like
popular blogging platforms; e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/&quot;&gt;Drupal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joomla.org/&quot;&gt;Joomla&lt;/a&gt;, etc;
nor something custom built on a web framework; like &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubyonrails.org/&quot;&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.djangoproject.com/&quot;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;; for something as simple as building a few short HTML pages in the
form of posts. So something static that did not need too many dependencies like
a database and mostly just assisted with pulling together a handful of HTML
templates to build a page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This probably could have been easily achieved by grabbing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://html5boilerplate.com/&quot;&gt;boilerplate HTML5
template&lt;/a&gt; and adding a couple of paragraph tags to fill out the majority of
the post (however that just felt tedious), but during my search of popular
programming frameworks, patterns, ideas and just news, I came across &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;
cause of its integration support within &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; (since it was created by one
of its founders and all).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It exposed me to the idea of Markdown (if I had not already came across it
within the excellent Railscasts) and how in combination with &lt;a href=&quot;http://shopify.github.io/liquid/&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt;
templates achieved the goals that I was looking for, mentioned above. Markdown
itself was teasure, its simple to digest syntax helps to cut down on the excess
of information throw at you when dealing with HTML, whilst also separating or
keeping the concerns of styles to a minimum from the contents of the content
(something I find Microsoft Word encourages procastination with).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I have already rambled on about why I like Ruby toolchain present in
Jekyll, without actually getting to the point of this website and being
distracted by fruitless endavours with constently adjusting the style or size of
the text in front me. Anywho …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to use this website to write down and scratch out some programming ideas
going forward, which has in the past either not been done, done in my head (if
even that counts), across multiple &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;~/Notes&lt;/code&gt; [Git] repositories or folders on
different computers or even just loose pieces of paper (oh gosh … soo many
paper notes :( ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One other thing I hope to do. I am going to look more at getting started at
programming (again), since my hiatus from work due to mental health reasons, to
hopefully teach or help someone indirectly, whilst also looking at comparing and
contrasting various programming languages that I have use in the past, to the
ones I am using now, as well as others I might us in the future (you know
whatever ever popular that week or everyone is jumping ship to).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that might be a lot to expect of myself, and in way a is sort of
proclamation of my New Years Resolution (if I need one), but right now I want
this to be more than just a flash in the pan or spur of the moment and look for
forward to the rest 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 12:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/01/01/welcome-to-my-website/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/01/01/welcome-to-my-website/</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
